

RYAN DEVAULT

PHONE: 615-904-5633

E-MAIL: CTRLVAULTDEL51@GMAIL.COM

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

ABOUT ME

Prior to my enrollment at Nashville Software School, I worked as both a public and private accountant but decided to make a career change into programming. This change was and is the best decision I have ever made; I look forward to coding and learning something new every day.

TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER APPRENTICESHIP

Nashville Software School (November 2020 - Current)

An intensive, six=month full-time program teaching the skills and technologies necessary to become a full-stack software developer

- Development of applications with current popular tech stacks, including JavaScript (ES6), HTML5, CSS3, React
- Git & GitHub version control
- Remote collaboration
- Design of wireframes, ERDs and data flow charts

PROJECTS

PERSONAL

BOARD & HOARD

https://github.com/CtrlVaultDel/nss-board-and-hoard

A CRUD web application built with React which allows users to search for board games based off their chosen search criteria and save them to their hoard (library). The project uses the lessons we learned up to this point, including use of local and external APIs, the React Library and granting users the ability to save, edit and delete board games in their library.

NUTSHELL

GROUP

https://github.com/nss-day-cohort-45/nutyshell-running-with-scissors-1

This web application was a collaborative effort developed by using JavaScript, HTML, and CSS. The purpose of the app is to serve as a social dashboard with friends, articles, events, a to-do list, and a chat feature. My contribution was aiding in the construction of the wireframe & ERD and the development of the articles components.

EXPERIENCE

CORPORATE STAFF ACCOUNTANT

Marquee Dental Partners (February 2020 - August 2020)

- Regularly worked with QuickBooks software.
- Reconciled bank statements monthly.
- Assisted Accounting Manager and Controller with month-end close.
- Spoke with suppliers to make orders or update information.

GENERAL CONTRACTOR ASSISTANT

DeVault Homes, Inc. (November 2019 - February 2020)

CORPORATE STAFF ACCOUNTANT

Edmondson, Betzler & Dame, PLLC. (August 2018 - November 2019)

- Performed audit tests, including cash, inventory, fixed assets, accrued expenses & accounts payable.
- Assisted in the process of end-of-year financial audits.
- Prepared working papers, reports and supporting documentation for audit findings.
- Prepared individual, trust, partnership and corporate tax returns

SUPERINTENDENT

DeVault Homes, Inc. (May 2009 - August 2018)

- Performed regular job site observations
- Obtained building permits
- Digitally archived weekly process of all assigned custom home projects
- Determined project schedule

EDUCATION

FULL STACK DEVELOPMENT BOOTCAMP Nashville Software School (November 2020 - Current)

MACC: ACCOUNTING

Middle Tennessee State University (December 2016)

BBA: ACCOUNTING

Middle Tennessee State University (December 2013)